NIRVAN BAJRACHARYA

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/nirvanbajracharya

Github: https://github.com/Agentnir18

Portfolio: https://agentnir18.github.io/portfolio/

nirvan.bajracharya@gmail.com +971 52 978 6369 Sharjah, United Arab Emirates

ABOUT ME

Specializing in Frontend Development and Data Analysis, and keen on transitioning into an Al Engineer. A skilled programmer with expertise in Python and JavaScript, and is dedicated to continuous learning and advancing their knowledge in the field of computer science. Additionally, possess a creative flair, and excellence in Illustrations and UI/UX design. Known for being a quick learner, with strong analytical skills and attention to detail in debugging and optimizing code.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

October 2020 - June 2023

University of West London (First Class Honors)

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Artificial Intelligence, Databases and Analytics, Applied Software Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Falcon Hackathon

July 2024 - August 2024

Frontend Developer

- · Worked with a team of 6 people to create Story Wise
- · Developed the project with Git for version control

Geekle Hackathon

July 2024 - August 2024

Frontend Developer & QA Tester

- 1st Place Winner in Geekle Hackathon Phase 2: Solution Mapper
- Worked with a team of 10 people to create a Diagram Solution Mapper using React Flow
- · Created tests for Claude AI to generate Mermaid Diagram from user inputs

TCR Innovation Sept - Nov 2022

Data Analyst Intern

- · Learned Data processing methods in Python
- · To train Machine Learning models

MindChamps 2020 - 2021

Illustrator and Web Designer (Internship)

- Tasked to make illustrations for their blog posts
- Created pages of their website
- Designed their current logo

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Programming: Python, Javascript, HTML/CSS, C++, C#, Java

Frameworks: React, Tailwind, Next.js, NodeJS, React Native, Flask, Tkinter, Pygame, OpenCV, JQuery

Databases: Oracle/SQL, MongoDB

Data Analytics: Excel, Microsoft PowerBl, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib **Others:** Photoshop, Illustrator, Blender, Figma, Office 365, Git, Linux, Wordpress, BurpSuite

PROJECTS

Story Wise (Generative Al App)

Using React, Tailwind, HTML/CSS, JavaScript,

- Making users understand scientific topics with ease by stories
- Designed the whole GUI using React and Tailwind containing Chat page, Home page, Collection page, etc.
- Features containing Sitcom scenario scripts generations for user engagement

Food Hygine Rating System (FHRS) App

Using React Native, Expo, HTML/CSS, JavaScript,

- Integrated FHRS API into the mobile app to present map location, rating values, establishments, etc.
- · Designed the GUI using React Native containing Maps, Onboarding Screen, BottomSheet, etc.
- · Navigating pages using Expo Router
- · Features containing Bookmark and Share on social apps

Form Manager Site

Using Flask, SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, JQuery

- · Used JQuery to drag and save positions of forms for priority management
- · Allows CRUD functionality for forms in a user-friendly layout
- · Integrated the site with REST API architecture and stored data in a local database

Al Art Canvas (ML Application)

Using Python, Tkinter, OpenCV

- Generates images from semantic input giving control of how image should generate
- · Style transfer feature added where images can merge with art styles
- Implemented the app with SPADE ML model to generate images
- · Designed the GUI of the app using python library called Tkinter

CERTIFICATES

Geekle Hackathon Phase 2 Winner

Geekle

Skills: Javascrpit · HTML/CSS · React · QA Testing

Data Analysis Using Python

IBM

Skills: Data Analysis · Jupyter · Python (Programming Language)

<u>Data Science with Machine Learning and Python Internship Program January 2023</u>

TCR Innovation

Skills: Data Analysis · Jupyter · Python (Programming Language)

Full Stack Web Development with Flask

Linkedin

Skills: Full-Stack Development · Flask

Advanced Python: Working With Data

Linkedin

Skills: Data Analysis \cdot Jupyter \cdot Python (Programming Language) \cdot Data Management